EPISODE 7
（第 7 集）
Gwanghwamun?
光化門？
What? We're in the Joseon Dynasty period?
什麼？我們在朝鮮王朝時代嗎？
Whenever this is, we find Hong-joo first.
不管了，先去找紅酒
Geez, seriously.
真是的
What the--
這是…
Moo-yeong, no! Don't breathe!
無影，不對！不要呼吸！
What's this? Hey!
這是什麼？哎呀！
-Hey, Moo-yeong! -I can't untie the ropes!
-無影！ -我解不開繩子！
Oh, gosh--
真是的…
No, no, no! Ladies, no. Let's talk it out, huh?
別這樣！各位女士，有話好說
Let's talk! Come on!
談談吧！拜託啦！
Hey, Moo-yeong!
無影！
We're not dead. What is this?
我們沒死，這是什麼？
This is fake blood.
是假血
It's a waste to throw away an expensive knife that's become blunt.
這麼貴的刀，變鈍就扔掉實在可惜
Here we go.
來
Just push and pull a few times with this versatile knife sharpener.
用這款多功能磨刀器來回磨幾下
Wow! It's like a brand-new sword!
哇！這把刀又恢復如新了！
MAGIC SWORD SHARPENER
（神奇磨刀器）
The ergonomic design ensures a secure grip
設計符合人體工學，抓握牢固
-with no slippage. -And cut! Okay!
-不打滑 -停！好了！
Change for the next scene. Hurry!
換下一場戲的佈景，快點！
IN SUPPORT OF JANGSAN TIGER'S BRIDE
（贊助《萇山虎的新娘》）
Let's get up. We'll resume in ten!
起來吧，十分鐘後繼續拍攝！
Give me that.
給我
"Jangsan Tiger's Bride"?
《萇山虎的新娘》？
It's a TV series set. It's not even the Joseon Dynasty period.
這是電視劇片場，根本不是朝鮮王朝
So this is the world he created?
這就是萇山虎創造的世界嗎？
First, let's get off this damn set.
我們先離開這個該死的片場吧
Is this a TV series or a damn commercial?
這是在拍電視劇還是廣告啊？
The script is crap, and it's not even complete!
腳本超爛的，還不完整！
-We need an extra bucketful of blood. -Get me corn syrup and pigment.
-我們還需要滿滿一桶血 -拿玉米糖漿和色素來
Look at the details. It looks like an actual set.
你看這些細節，和真正的片場沒差別
But how is this possible?
但這怎麼可能呢？
No matter how powerful a demon, he can't cross over time.
無論一個妖怪的力量有多強大 他也無法跨越時間
-Where on earth could Hong-joo be? -Gosh. Damn it.
-紅酒到底會在哪裡？ -可惡
-Hey, is the female lead late again? -She just arrived, sir.
-女一號又遲到了？ -她剛到
A-listers think they're everything, huh?
一線明星總是愛耍大牌
Damn it. How do we find her? Let's go look over there.
該死，是要去哪找人？去那邊看看吧
Welcome, ma'am.
歡迎妳，女士
-Hong-joo! -I'm so glad you're safe.
-紅酒！ -妳沒事就好
What's this?
想幹嘛？
Who are they?
他們是誰？
This is male number four and five.
這是男四號和男五號
Since when do supporting actors get to talk to me?
從什麼時候起 配角也能跟我說話了？
Apologies, ma'am. They're new. Sorry.
對不起，他們是新人，抱歉
-Remove 'em. -No, Hong-joo. That's not…
-叫他們走開 -不，紅酒，那不是…
-Hey! -Please move.
-喂！ -請讓一下
I'm so sorry, ma'am…
真抱歉，女士…
-That's Hong-joo, right? -Why can't she recognize us?
-那是紅酒沒錯吧？ -她為什麼不認得我們？
Is she bewitched by Jangsan Tiger?
難道被萇山虎蠱惑了？
This won't do. Let's drag her out.
這樣不行，直接把她拖走好了
But why is she the main lead, while I'm some minor supporting role?
話說回來，為什麼她是女一號 我只是一個小小的配角？
Why are you number four when I'm number five, huh?
而且你是男四號，我是男五號？
-Does that matter now? -Of course it does!
-這個重要嗎？ -當然重要！
Jangsan Tiger, that prick…
萇山虎那個混帳…
Ready, action!
預備，開始！
-Where are we now? -Why are we here?
-這是什麼地方？ -我們為什麼會在這裡？
Hey, your clothes-- Hat-- Geez, what's this now?
你的衣服…帽子… 天哪，現在又是怎麼回事？
Who's there?
誰在那裡？
Hong-joo.
紅酒
-It's me, Moo-yeong. -It's Moo-yeong.
-我是無影啊 -是無影
-Moo-yeong? -Why can't you remember me, your friend?
-無影？ -妳怎麼不記得我這個朋友了？
I got amnesia after I fell in the lake.
我墜湖之後失憶了
Now I've seen everything. Hey, forget this crap and come with us.
我算是見識到了 不要在這裡胡鬧了，跟我們走
-I won't go. No, I can't. -Why not?
-我不會走，也不能走 -為什麼？
Because he is my only groom.
因為他是我唯一的新郎
Get a grip, you brat! You're bewitched by Jangsan Tiger. Come.
醒醒吧，死丫頭！ 妳被萇山虎蠱惑了，快走
Cut! Stop filming!
停！別拍了！
-Gosh, seriously! -Hey!
-天哪，真是的！ -喂！
-Oh, my! -What's this now?
-天哪！ -又怎麼了？
What agency are you from, huh? How dare you smack an actress!
你是哪家經紀公司的？ 竟敢毆打女演員！
My goodness. Where did you find these pricks?
天哪，這些混帳是從哪裡找來的？
-Sorry, ma'am. Let's do another take. -I'm so annoyed!
-對不起，女士，我們重拍吧 -氣死我了！
Says who?
誰說的？
I won't go. No, I can't.
我不會走，也不能走
Because he is my only groom.
因為他是我唯一的新郎
-Is this the scene from earlier? -So it seems.
-這是剛才那場戲嗎？ -好像是
-Shit-- Enough with this crap! -Cut! Take three!
-可惡，不要再胡鬧了！ -停！第三拍！
-I won't go. No, I can't. -Sheesh.
-我不會走，也不能走 -哎呀
Cut! Take four!
停！第四拍！
I won't go. No, I can't.
我不會走，也不能走
Because he is my only groom.
因為他是我唯一的新郎
This is driving me nuts! Why are we repeating lines?
我要瘋掉了！ 為什麼要重複這段台詞？
Hey, there's a script.
給你，這是腳本
-Because he is my only groom. -"Sure.
-因為他是我唯一的新郎 -“當然
Jangsan Tiger is stronger and more beautiful than us.
萇山虎比我們更強大、更帥氣
-But we're here to save you." -What's with the script? Seriously.
-但我們是來救妳的” -這是什麼狗屁腳本？真是的
Just read it.
乖乖念吧
"Moo-yeong, shouldn't we leave, for Hong-joo's happiness?
“無影，為了紅酒的幸福 我們也該走了吧？
Open parenthesis. Speaks in tears. Close parenthesis.
左括弧，眼含淚光，右括弧
-Hong-joo, you belong here." -That's so not…
-紅酒，妳屬於這裡” -一派胡言…
You may have been my friends,
你們是我的朋友沒錯
but you're a fake and you're a villain.
但你們一個是冒牌貨，一個是壞人
You think I'm a fake?
妳認為我是冒牌貨？
There are two of you.
總共有兩個你
And the opium addict in Manchuria is the real one.
在滿洲吸鴉片那個癮君子才是真的
HONG-JOO: THERE ARE TWO OF YOU…
（紅酒：總共有兩個你…）
What? How is this line in the script?
搞什麼？腳本裡怎麼會有這句台詞？
That bastard knows more about us than we imagined.
那個混蛋對我們的瞭解 超乎我們的想像
This feels bad. Let's get her out.
感覺不妙，把帶她走
The pain of sending them off--
趕走他們，我心痛不已
I should comfort myself with this makgeolli.
喝一瓶馬格利酒撫平心痛吧
MOUNTAIN GOD MAKGEOLLI MADE FROM 100% DOMESTIC RICE
（山神馬格利酒，純國產大米釀造）
Long-term, low-temperature ripening-fermentation method
使用長期低溫熟化發酵法
preserves fresh yeast.
保存新鮮酵母
Plus, no burping or hangovers!
而且喝完不打嗝不宿醉！
-And cut! Okay! -Great.
-停！好了！ -很好
-Great work, ma'am! -Gosh, it's seriously so heavy! Move it.
-辛苦了！ -天哪，這帽子有夠重！走快點
Great work, ma'am.
演得真好，女士
-Hurry up! -I'm hungry. Out of my way!
-快點！ -我餓了，讓開！
What do we do?
怎麼辦？
Hong-joo's in such a state. Plus, we can't get out of here on our own.
紅酒狀態不對 而且我們自己也出不去
-He's much stronger than I thought. -Hey, let's just burn this whole set.
-他比我想像中強大許多 -我們燒掉整個片場吧
-Will that be okay? -Of course, it's an illusion anyway.
-可行嗎？ -當然可行，反正都是幻象
Light 'em up.
點火
-What are you doing? -I can't start a fire.
-你在幹嘛？ -我變不出火焰
-You try. -Gosh.
-你試試 -天哪
Damn it! What's going on?
該死！怎麼回事？
-Lightning, thunder-- Nothing works. -Our skills mustn't work here.
-雷電什麼的都召喚不出 -一定是我們的法力在這裡無效
Wait, hold on.
等一下
The show's called Jangsan Tiger's Bride.
這部劇叫《萇山虎的新娘》
If Hong-joo is the bride…
既然紅酒是新娘
he must be in here too.
萇山虎一定也在這裡
Let's catch the prick first.
我們先抓住那個混帳
Yeon and Moo-yeong did what?
阿硯和無影做了什麼？
How dare they recklessly jump into such a place?
他們竟敢不計後果地跳進那種地方？
-What kind of place is it? -Look.
-那是什麼地方？ -你看
This is the Living, and this is the Dead.
這是陽間，這是陰間
The Path of the Damned lies between the two.
詛咒之路位於兩者之間
It seems like reality at first glance,
一眼看上去和現實沒差
but it's a playground for demons thousands of years old!
其實是千年妖怪的遊樂場！
It's a place neither we, nor the gods, carelessly enter!
那是我們和眾神 都不敢隨便進入的地方啊！
On top of that, it's Jangsan Tiger.
何況對方還是萇山虎
And who exactly is this guy?
這傢伙究竟是誰？
An impersonator.
他是擅長模仿的妖怪
Once upon a time, there lived a tiger at Jangsan,
很久以前，萇山住著一隻老虎
that had a knack for imitating others.
有模仿他物的本領
At first, it imitated the sound of beasts. Then, the sound of humans.
起初牠只是模仿野獸的聲音 後來逐漸模仿起人聲
And finally, it began imitating the gods.
最後開始模仿神
-By god, you mean-- -It coveted the place of a mountain god.
-妳說的神是… -牠曾覬覦山神之位
-He wanted to become a mountain god? -He doesn't only imitate voices.
-萇山虎想做山神？ -他不僅能模仿聲音
He can imitate everything one sees, hears, or says.
還能模仿別人 看過、聽過、講過的一切
Including one's memories.
包括記憶
How does Yeon intend to return?
阿硯打算如何回來？
He has a silk thread tied to him, and Lord Lee Rang has the skein.
他身上綁著一根絲線 線綹在李朗大人手上
The path remains open?
通道還開著？
-You imbeciles! -Why? What's wrong?
-你們這些蠢貨！ -怎麼了？
He'll try to cross over from that world.
他會設法從那個世界穿過來
Lee Rang is in danger!
李朗有危險！
What?
什麼？
Hello? Hello?
喂？
-Koo Shin-ju? -Lord Lee Rang! He's coming!
-具申炷？ -李朗大人！他要來了！
-What are you talking about? -There's no time. Listen to me carefully.
-你在說什麼？ -沒時間了，你仔細聽我說
Put your blood on the thread. Hurry!
把你的血塗在絲線上，快！
Okay. I did it.
我塗好了
So everything's prepared, huh?
看來一切都準備好了
Prepared for what?
什麼準備？
For me to enter that world.
讓我進入那個世界的準備
He's not Shin-ju!
他不是申炷！
-He's not picking up? -The line's busy. I'll go check.
-他沒接電話嗎？ -正在通話中，我過去看看
Go tell him that whatever he does, he mustn't get blood on the thread.
你去告訴他，無論如何 絕不能讓絲線沾到血
-It's like an invitation to them! -Yes, sir.
-那等於向妖怪發出邀請！ -知道了
If he lets go of the thread,
如果他放開絲線
-the way back will disappear. -Lord Lee Rang won't let go of it. Ever.
-回來的路就會消失 -李朗大人絕對不會放手的
I can't believe it's Jangsan Tiger.
居然是萇山虎
-Is it a coincidence they encountered him? -I'm sure it was Moo-yeong.
-他們遇到他是巧合嗎？ -一定是無影幹的
He needs Jangsan Tiger to fix his body.
他需要萇山虎來修復他的身體
While oblivious to his deep resentment of mountain gods…
連萇山虎對山神充滿怨恨都不顧了
Honey, what should we do about the kids?
老婆，我們該拿這些孩子怎麼辦？
They have no choice but to figure it out for themselves.
他們只能自己想辦法
To bring Hong-joo back from that world,
想要把紅酒從那個世界帶回來
eventually,
最終
they'll have to save each other.
他們必須互相救助
-I'll take one. -Yes.
-我拿一杯 -好
Excuse me.
打擾一下
So, I was wondering. Who wrote this script?
請問腳本是誰寫的？
The director wrote it himself.
導演親自寫的
-The director? -Yes.
-導演？ -是的
-Director, sir. -Yeah?
-導演 -嗯？
-Well, are you Jangsan Tiger? -What are you talking about, punk?
-你是萇山虎嗎？ -臭小子，胡說什麼？
If you don't know, then let's have a beating first.
如果你不知道，先揍一頓再說吧
What, punk?
什麼，臭小子？
You earned this.
這是你自找的
Who told you to write this crap? Huh?
誰叫你寫這種垃圾的？
-Sir, I just did what I was told. -Who told you to do it?
-先生，我只是按吩咐辦事 -誰的吩咐？
It was…
是…
Who was it again?
是誰來著？
-Who the hell is Jangsan Tiger? -Jangsan Tiger?
-萇山虎到底是誰？ -萇山虎？
Hey, hey!
喂！
Rang, are you there?
阿朗，你在嗎？
Lee Yeon?
李硯？
-No. You're not Lee Yeon, are you? -It is me!
-不，你不是李硯，對吧？ -是我啊！
Pull me in. Hurry! Moo-yeong's been attacked.
拉我進去，快！無影遇襲了
-Prove that you're him. -I said I'll buy you naengmyeon!
-你先證明你是李硯 -我說過要請你吃冷麵
I don't have much time. Hurry!
沒時間了，快點！
Where are you?
你在哪裡？
Playing with food brings bad fortune.
玩食物不吉利
It's for my darling.
這是為我親愛的準備的
Wow. Kids these days will say anything in front of a widow, huh?
天哪，現在的孩子 在寡婦面前講話都毫不避諱的嗎？
What kind of person was your husband?
妳老公是個什麼樣的人？
They say a man's feelings change like the colors of a rainbow tteok,
都說男人的感情 像彩虹年糕的顏色一樣說變就變
but his love for me never changed.
但他對我的愛從沒變過
Then, what happened?
後來怎麼了？
I fell for a demon's trickeries.
我中了一個妖怪的詭計
He cared for me so dearly,
他那麼疼愛我
but I couldn't protect him.
我卻沒能保護他
Yeo-hee.
汝熙
Don't you lose him like I did.
不要像我那樣失去他
Yes, ma'am.
好
-This must be an expensive shoot. -Yeah.
-這場戲一定很花錢 -是啊
It's you, huh?
是妳吧？
-Pardon? -Jangsan Tiger.
-什麼？ -萇山虎
Whatever that is, it's not me.
我不知道那是什麼，但肯定不是我
In these genres, the first person you meet is the suspect.
在這類影片裡 第一個遇到的人就是嫌疑犯
Plus, the rice puffs you're eating--
而且妳吃的磅米芳
That's what Hong-joo was eating during the corner game.
正是紅酒在四角遊戲中吃的東西
One of the staff over there gave it to me earlier.
這是那邊一位工作人員給我的
You liar.
妳撒謊
I'm not lying.
我沒有
It's not a lie!
那不是謊話！
Hong-joo?
紅酒！
What the hell are you?
妳到底是誰？
Since the ancient times, I was called an impersonator.
自古以來，他們就叫我模仿者
I can become anything.
我能變幻成任何東西
You bastard. How dare you!
混帳，你好大的膽子！
Let's play some more.
繼續玩吧
This is the world you've created.
這畢竟是你創造的世界
-That's… -I stole some of your memories.
-那是… -我偷了你的部分記憶
You die in the Joseon era, but wake to an unfamiliar future.
你死在朝鮮時代 卻在陌生的未來甦醒
No friends or family by your side.
身邊沒有朋友，也沒有家人
Was it called a television? You started imitating the people on it.
這是叫電視吧？ 你開始模仿電視裡的人
-Fake crying and laughing. -Shut your mouth.
-假哭、假笑 -閉嘴
-You're just like me. The same monster. -No!
-你和我一樣，都是怪物 -不！
-No. I'm nothing like you-- -You're the one who called for me.
-不，我和你完全不一樣… -是你召喚我來的
This woman…
這個女人…
-will die because of you. -No!
-會被你害死的 -不要！
Now, no one will be left by your side. You'll wander in the dark forever.
現在你身邊不會有人了 你將永遠徘徊在黑暗中
Like when you became stone.
就像你變成石柱那樣
Don't torture my friend with that face.
不要頂著那張臉折磨我朋友
Well, look at you?
看看你
What? The duduri doesn't work on you?
怎麼回事？豆豆里對你沒有用？
You don't know much about your friend, huh?
你對你朋友瞭解不深吧？
Don't insult us.
少侮辱我們
You're a mere impersonator too afraid to show your face, so don't you dare.
你只是一個不敢露臉的模仿者 少在那裡胡說
Still arrogant as always, Lee Yeon. Mountain god of Baekdudaegan.
你還是那麼自大，李硯 白頭大幹山的山神
At one point, I wanted to be you.
我還一度想要成為你呢
You could never in a million years. You're just a clown.
你永遠都別想成為我 你只是個跳樑小丑
Moo-yeong!
無影！
I'll give you an hour from now.
我給你們一個小時的時間
Try to save this woman, if you can.
有本事就來救這個女人吧
You're not gods in this world.
在這個世界裡，你們不是神
I am.
我才是
What's this?
這是什麼？
EDEN BOUTIQUE
（伊甸精品店）
The setting's changed to Gyeongseong.
佈景換回京城了
One hour left. We must find Hong-joo in time.
只剩一小時，我們必須及時找到紅酒
How did you find that bastard?
你是如何發現那個混帳的？
The rice puffs Hong-joo was eating.
紅酒吃過那個磅米芳
He say anything else?
他還說了什麼？
He can peek into our memories.
他能窺探我們的記憶
So this stage was made from stealing my memories?
原來這個舞台 是用我被盜的記憶搭建的？
Since you and Hong-joo haven't been to the future.
畢竟你和紅酒都沒有去過未來
But Moo-yeong…
但是無影…
Why didn't my duduri work on Jangsan Tiger?
為什麼我的豆豆里 對萇山虎不起作用？
I'm not sure.
我不知道
Since it wasn't the main body?
也許是因為那不是他的本體？
You guys the Mountain God gang?
你們是山神幫？
Yeah, you're right. But who are you guys?
沒錯，你們是誰？
I said who are you?
我問你們是誰？
I'm Kim Du-han.
我是金斗漢
-Kim Du-han of Jongno. -Mr. Ahn Jae-mo--
-鐘路金斗漢 -安在模先生…
No way.
不會吧
Gosh, I'm losing my mind!
天哪，我要瘋了！
-Get them. -Out of the blue?
-打 -說打就打？
Oh, dear. Why are they spinning?
天哪，他們為什麼要轉圈？
Why are they spinning?
轉圈幹嘛？
You have some lousy skills.
你們的功夫太遜了
What's he saying?
他在胡說什麼？
I've practically won this fight.
這場打鬥我贏定了
I was already reading your moves.
我已識破你們的招式
Bring it on.
放馬過來吧
Shit. Why's he so good?
該死，他怎麼這麼厲害？
Spinning again? He keeps spinning!
又轉圈？他一直轉圈！
I wonder if their teeth are intact after getting beat like that.
不知道經過一頓暴打之後 他們的牙齒還好嗎？
Stop worrying about your teeth. You have Gyeongseong dental insurance!
再也不必擔心牙齒 京城牙科保險令您無憂！
DENTAL PROCEDURE COSTS DON'T WORRY!
（牙科診療費用，不必擔憂！）
FOR IMPLANTS, CROWNS CALL 0001-2570
（植牙、牙冠診療 請撥打0001-2570）
Not only prosthetic treatment, but also implants, bridges and dentures.
不僅涵蓋假牙治療 還包括植牙、牙橋和假牙費用
Gyeongseong dental insurance for costly procedures.
京城牙科保險 為昂貴的療程保駕護航
Early termination fees: less than the insurance premium if none.
提前終止費：無退費或低於保險費
Where the hell are you? Come out!
你到底在哪裡？出來！
-Boss, please save me… -Who's there?
-老大，請救救我 -是誰？
Is that you, Underboss?
副頭目，是你嗎？
Yes, sir. It's me.
對，是我
Please cut this thread. It's choking my neck…
求你剪斷絲線，它勒住我的脖子了…
I can't breathe…
我不能呼吸了
How funny. Your height doesn't match.
真奇怪，你的身高不對
Please… Cut this!
求你…剪斷它！
You bastard!
混蛋！
-Rang, let go of the thread! -Shut up!
-阿朗，放開絲線！ -閉嘴！
You must let go to live!
你要放手才能活命！
Lord Lee Yeon is using you.
李硯大人在利用你
Get a grip! He'll just use you, only to abandon you again!
醒醒吧 利用你之後，他只會再次拋棄你！
-Just cut the silk thread! -Just stop!
-剪斷絲線！ -閉嘴！
Why…
為什麼…
Why can't I let go of this?
為什麼我不捨得放手？
Are you that thing?
你就是那個東西嗎？
The thing that's born between my father and a human?
我父親和一個人類生下的東西？
Are you a fox too?
你也是狐狸嗎？
Whether you live as a human or a fox, it's your choice.
做人還是做狐狸，你自己選
But remember this, kid:
但是孩子，你要記住
There's no salvation for those who don't save themselves.
不懂得自救的人得不到救贖
Wait for me!
等等我！
Wait for me, my brother.
等我一下，哥哥
Ages ago…
很多年前…
the hand that held mine, who was abandoned by a human mother,
那隻手牽著被人類母親拋棄的我
was annoyingly warm…
居然異常的溫暖
That's why this…
所以我覺得…
felt like…
這仿佛是…
the last link I had to Lee Yeon.
我與李硯之間最後一絲牽絆
I won't let go…
我不會放手的
Try all you want.
有本事儘管使出來
I won't ever, ever let go!
我絕對不會放手的！
YEON TALK - LEE YEON
（《阿硯說》，李硯）
"ASPIRING TALK SHOW HOST" CHEON MOO-YEONG
（有志向的脫口秀主持人，千無影）
CHALLENGE QUIZ KING
（《挑戰答題王》）
The setting's changed again.
佈景又變了
So, it's a quiz show this time.
這次是益智問答節目
He's playing games with us, switching between TV channels.
他不停地換台，和我們玩遊戲
Well, the rules are simple.
規則很簡單
Whether we win or lose,
無論輸贏
we do what we must to move on to the next level.
我們都要拼盡全力進入下一關
You'll dance to his tune again?
你又要按照他的意思做？
All we have to do is save Hong-joo. You don't have other ideas, no?
我們的任務是救紅酒 你也沒有其他辦法吧？
Let's give it a try.
試試吧
Great. Who will it be this time?
好極了，這次又會是誰？
Nice to meet you.
很高興見到你們
Yes, hello, hello.
你好…
Hello there. It's a pleasure to meet you both. Hello?
你們好，很榮幸認識兩位，你好
Ho-yeong?
哥哥？
-Are you here to solve the quiz? -Moo-yeong, that's not your brother.
-你是來答題的嗎？ -無影，他不是你哥哥
Why that sick little…
那該死的混帳…
I'm going to kill him.
我要殺了他
Will you give up on the quiz?
你要放棄答題嗎？
When your girlfriend is dying at this very moment?
在女友命懸一線的危急關頭放棄嗎？
Cheon Moo-yeong, no!
千無影，不要衝動！
-Don't fall for his provocation. -How dare you.
-不要被他的挑釁沖昏頭 -你好大的膽子
How dare you!
你好大的膽子！
Let's sit down, okay? We don't have much time.
坐下吧？我們的時間不多了
Today's show is a "best friends" special.
今天的節目是“最佳好友”特輯
I'll ask you one thing before we start.
開始之前，我先問你一個問題
You two were best friends, right?
你們兩人是最好的朋友吧？
If so, why did you kill his older brother?
既然如此，你為何要殺死他哥哥？
Gosh, is this too delicate a question?
天哪，這問題太難回答了嗎？
Because we swore to protect each other, no matter what.
因為我們曾經發過誓 無論如何都要守護彼此
That was the only way I could protect you that day.
那天只有殺死他，我才能守護你
Oh, my. Do you agree with his words?
天哪，你認同他的說法嗎？
Ho-yeong.
哥哥
Something's wrong. This isn't right.
不對勁，不該是這樣的
Don't kill him, please!
求你不要殺他！
No!
不！
No…
不…
Do you agree with your friend's words?
你認同你朋友的說法嗎？
I disagree.
不認同
Why? But your brother tried to kill you?
為什麼？但是你哥哥想殺你呀
You pricks.
混蛋
What makes you think you can speak about my brother?
你有什麼資格議論我哥哥？
-Stop it! -This is all your fault!
-別說了！ -都是你的錯！
I asked you to give him a chance.
我要你給他一次機會的
That he must have a good reason.
他一定有他的苦衷
But you didn't believe me.
可是你不相信我
This is it.
原來如此
-This is what he wants from us. -What?
-這才是萇山虎的目的 -什麼？
I'm talking about this stupid show!
我指的是這個愚蠢的節目！
He intended for us to fight each other.
他故意引我們起內鬨
Moo-yeong, he is afraid of mountain gods.
無影，他害怕山神
Come on, I doubt it.
拜託，我看未必
You stay out of this.
少管閒事
Hey. You're watching me, no?
喂，你在看我吧？
We are your inferiority complex.
你的自卑感是因為我們
We are the mountain gods you could never become.
我們是你永遠做不成的山神
And the reaper's here for your neck.
死神要來收割你的性命了
Have your will ready.
準備好你的遺囑吧
CHANGE CHANNEL
（轉台）
I'll kill you.
我要殺了你
-Boss, cut this silk thread for me! -You're the one who'll be killed.
-老大，幫我剪斷這根絲線！ -會被殺死的人只有你
-Too bad you won't get your naengmyeon. -Shut up!
-可惜你吃不到冷麵了 -閉嘴！
-Boss! -Shut up, all of you!
-老大！ -你們都閉嘴！
Are you inside? It's me, Yeo-hee.
你在裡面嗎？是我，汝熙
Bullshit. You think you can fool me again?
胡說，你以為我還會上當嗎？
I made late-night snacks for you.
我幫你做了宵夜
Snacks or whatnot, get lost!
什麼宵夜不宵夜的，滾！
Come in. I'm waiting for you.
進來吧，我在等妳
Don't come. That voice isn't me!
不要進來，那個聲音不是我！
-I told you to come in. -Don't come in!
-我叫妳進來 -不要進來！
I'll kill you if you do!
妳若進來，我就殺了妳！
I'm going in, okay?
我要進去了
I don't need you, so please just leave!
我不需要妳，拜託妳走開！
Are you okay?
你沒事吧？
I told you not to come in.
我叫妳不要進來的
I promised, remember?
我承諾過的，記得嗎？
I promised I'd protect you.
我承諾過要守護你
I'm unnecessarily indebted to you again…
我又白白欠妳一次人情…
This time, repay me all at once.
這次一起還給我吧
How?
怎麼還？
This is the thing.
是這樣的
I thought Jangsan Tiger had taken a peek into my head to make this TV show.
我以為萇山虎偷看過我的記憶 才拍出這檔電視節目
But?
但是呢？
I like rom-coms, so I didn't even watch the legendary TV show, Rustic Period.
我喜歡看浪漫喜劇 根本沒看過傳奇劇《野人時代》
What are you trying to say?
你想說什麼？
Can I trust you?
我能相信你嗎？
If you can't, cut me.
不信的話就直接砍了我吧
-You'll die a meaningless death here? -In return, save Hong-joo at all costs.
-你甘願在這裡白白死掉？ -作為交換，你要拼盡全力救紅酒
My life doesn't matter one bit.
我的命一點都不重要
What did you want to check?
你剛剛想要確認什麼？
If you're the Moo-yeong I know.
你是否是我認識的那個無影
So? Do you have an answer?
那你有得到答案嗎？
Yeah.
有
You laid down your life to save Hong-joo.
你願意犧牲自己的性命來救紅酒
Just like the Moo-yeong I know.
和我認識的無影一模一樣
Whatever I may be to you,
無論你如何看我
I don't intend to give up on either of you.
我都不打算放棄 你們兩個中的任何一個
There was one moment…
曾經…
I wanted to hear those words from you before.
我很想聽到你這麼說
There are rice puffs here too.
這裡也有磅米芳
-Isn't this too Hansel and Gretel? -What if Hong-joo left them?
-這也太像童話糖果屋的陷阱了吧？ -如果是紅酒留下的呢？
Okay, let's go then.
好吧，我們去看看
Who cares if a witch shows up now.
現在就算出現女巫也無所謂了
When the wedding is over,
婚禮結束後
you will be my bride forever.
妳將永遠成為我的新娘
We will perform the hapgeun ceremony signifying the bride and groom's union.
我們將進行 象徵新郎新娘結成夫妻的合巹禮
HAPGEUN CEREMONY - CUP TRADING RITUAL TO UNIFY A COUPLE
（合巹禮 象徵夫妻結合的交杯儀式）
Drink it.
喝掉
If you drink this, you can live in your fond memories…
喝掉它，妳就能永遠生活在…
forever.
快樂的記憶裡
Hong-joo.
紅酒
Hong-joo, you're safe.
紅酒，還好妳沒事
-Are you not injured? -Hey-- No, stay away!
-妳沒有受傷吧？ -不對，別過去！
Wake up, Hong-joo.
醒醒吧，紅酒
Her eyes are blank.
她的眼神很空洞
We took our matrimonial vows, you see.
我們是有過婚姻誓約的
So it was you?
原來是你？
She belongs to this world now.
她現在屬於這個世界了
She is Jangsan Tiger's bride now.
她是萇山虎的新娘了
Bullshit!
胡說！
Wow.
哇
If you wish to kill me, you will have to strike her first.
你們若想殺我，必須先過她這一關
Or you can live out your life in this damned world forever.
或者，你們可以 在這個被詛咒的世界裡過一輩子
I'm going home.
我要回家
I promised to eat naengmyeon with my brother.
我答應過請弟弟去吃冷麵的
Moo-yeong, take your sword out.
無影，拔劍吧
Just like he said, we must take her down to get to him.
他說得沒錯 我們必須先過她這一關才能殺死他
I can't do it.
我做不到
We have to. We're the only ones who can.
我們必須這麼做，只有我們做得到
Let's leave here with her.
我們帶紅酒離開這裡吧
I give you my word.
我保證
I, Lee Yeon, promise to protect you both with this sword, no matter what.
我，李硯，無論如何 都會用這把劍守護你們兩個
-Just trust me. -You idiot.
-相信我吧 -笨蛋
We protect each other.
我們要互相守護
I, Hong-joo, will soil this sword with the blood of hundreds and thousands
我，紅酒，將用無數鮮血染紅這把劍
to protect Yeon and Moo-yeong.
來守護阿硯和無影
Well, I wish to protect the both of you without slaying anyone or anything.
我希望我不用殺死任何東西 就能守護你們兩個
Let's swear
起誓吧
to protect each other no matter what.
無論如何都要守護彼此
Hey, stop tormenting him.
好了，別折磨他了
I can't do it.
我下不了手
I couldn't cut you to save my life.
我無法為了活命而刺殺妳
I came back for you.
我是為妳回來的
I'm alive because of you, Hong-joo.
我還活著都是因為妳啊，紅酒
Die.
去死吧
Stop this, Hong-joo.
住手，紅酒
Please stop.
請妳住手吧
Stop this.
停下來
And come with us.
跟我們走吧
Gosh, how pathetic.
天哪，真是無藥可救
Do they still believe such things will get through to her?
他們還相信這種勸說能打動她的心？
End them for good.
徹底了結他們
Will I die here?
我要死在這裡了嗎？
At a lousy place like this?
在這令人厭惡的地方？
By the hand of a best friend at that?
還死在最好的朋友手上？
I'm not afraid to die by your hand.
我不怕死在妳手上
Even if I die…
即便我死了…
you must live on, Hong-joo.
妳也必須活下去，紅酒
You must survive to return…
妳必須活著回到…
to where you belong.
屬於妳的地方
This is proof that the three of us are one.
這是我們三人同心的證據
Hey…
喂
Unlike Moo-yeong. I don't intend to die by you.
我和無影不一樣 我可不想死在妳手裡
Come back, Ryu Hong-joo.
回來吧，柳紅酒
Come back to us.
回到我們身邊
Geez, what the hell are they doing?
真是的，他們在幹嘛？
Let's go together…
我們一起走吧
As we always have.
就像每次一樣
The three of us together.
我們三個人一起走
Hey.
喂
Don't make Hong-joo cry.
不要惹哭紅酒
Don't make Hong-joo cry!
不要惹哭紅酒！
Guys, get up!
大家快起來！
Don't make her cry-- Don't make Hong-joo cry!
不要惹她哭，不要惹哭紅酒！
Stop that!
住手！
Bite me instead!
來咬我吧！
Moo-yeong!
無影！
Hong-joo, wake up.
紅酒，醒來吧
Come with us, okay?
跟我們走好不好？
Kill them. Kill 'em both!
殺死他們，殺死他們兩個！
That's right!
做得好！
Hong-joo…
紅酒…
What?
什麼？
How could you?
妳怎麼能？
You dared to play me like a puppet?
你竟敢把我當傀儡一樣玩弄？
Damn it, you crazy bitch.
該死，妳這個瘋婆子
Do not insult her.
不准侮辱她
We never lose when the three of us are together.
當我們三人同心時，絕不會輸
-You still get hurt on my behalf. -Your safety is all that matters.
-你還是替我受傷了 -只要妳平安就好
That's all I need.
那是我唯一的心願
We have no time. Let's hurry.
沒時間了，我們快走
Wait.
等一下
Where am I? I lost my memory, while playing the corner game.
這是哪裡？我玩四角遊戲時失憶了
-Mr. Cheon! -We'll talk after we leave this place.
-千先生！ -先離開這裡再說吧
-Let's go. -Come on.
-快走 -快
Careful, guys.
大家小心
Oh, my!
天哪！
Having no cars or taxis is driving me nuts!
沒有轎車也沒有計程車，我要瘋了！
Oh, hey! Ta-- Taxi!
喂，計程車！
-Let's go to Myoyeongak. -What?
-去妙緣閣 -什麼？
-Myoyeongak! -Myoyeongak.
-妙緣閣！ -妙緣閣
Departing to Myoyeongak!
向妙緣閣出發！
-Go! To Myoyeongak! -Go!
-出發！去妙緣閣！ -出發！
Excuse me, where did you get those shoes?
請問這雙鞋子是哪來的？
A young man gave it to me as a gift.
是一個年輕人送我的禮物
As a gift?
禮物？
He probably thinks of it as philanthropy.
他可能是在行善吧
Think of this as philanthropy, okay?
就當我們是在行善吧
Hey, you know me, right?
你認識我對不對？
-Wow. -So it is you?
-哇 -果然是你？
Hey! Damn you!
該死的！
-Come here, you prick! -Stay away!
-過來，混蛋！ -走開！
You bastard!
你這個混蛋！
You little thief. Give me back my shoes and wedding ring!
你這小偷，把我的鞋子和婚戒還來！
They're mine that I stole fair and square!
那是我憑本事偷來的！
You little bastard, die!
混蛋，去死吧！
Those muscles! Boss!
好厲害的肌肉！老大！
Why are you looking for your boss now, you pervert?
變態，現在找你老大做什麼？
Where's the way out?
出路在哪裡？
This way.
這邊
Come now.
來吧
-Go inside. -Hurry.
-進去 -快點
Moo-yeong? Cheon Moo-yeong!
無影？千無影！
Moo-yeong?
無影？
Moo-yeong!
無影！
Where's Lee Yeon?
李硯呢？
The door is closed.
門關上了
You left him there. Why? Why are you the only one back?
妳把他留在那裡了，為什麼？ 為什麼只有妳一個人回來？
We came together!
我們一起回來的！
We were all there…
我們都在的…
Cheon Moo-yeong. This is his doing.
千無影，是他幹的
He did this on purpose.
他是故意的
It can't be.
不可能
So it was you.
原來是你
You were the one who called on Jangsan Tiger.
是你召喚萇山虎的
I needed this.
我需要這個東西
A demon's essence of over thousands of years.
千年妖怪的精華
It's like medicine for my body.
是治癒我身體的良藥
At last.
終於
I reclaim my body at last, Lee Yeon.
我終於奪回身體了，李硯
And you are Red-white mask.
你就是紅白面具人
I am indeed.
沒錯
The one who threw you into this era,
那個將你帶入這個時代
and tried to kill you and your brother countless times.
無數次想要殺死你和你弟弟的人
-That was all me. -I was hoping otherwise.
-都是我 -我本來還抱有一絲幻想
-That it'd be anyone but you. -I lost everything because of you.
-不管是誰，都不會是你 -你害我失去了一切
My family, friends, and my mountain!
我的家人、朋友，還有我的山！
Including myself.
包括我自己
I hate those who blame others after living for over a thousand years.
我討厭那些活了一千多年 還在怪罪別人的人
Lee Yeon, you can't go home.
李硯，你沒辦法回家了
You will never see the woman you love either.
你也永遠見不到你愛的女人了
Cheon Moo-yeong.
千無影
I will kill you, if that's your wish.
既然你找死，我就殺了你
You had the wrong look from the start. I expected you'd pull something like this.
你從一開始就不對勁 我早就料到你會做出這種事
Rang.
阿朗
I told you not to trust him.
我叫你不要信任他的
I'm okay, but you're in danger. Get out of here.
我沒事，但你有危險，快離開這裡
Lay a finger on him, and I'll kill you.
敢動他一下，我就殺了你
What harm can a half-fox do?
一隻半狐能掀起什麼風浪？
If you want to kill him, kill me first.
想殺他的話，必須先殺死我
Don't you lay a finger on my little brother.
不准你動我弟弟一根汗毛
After butchering my brother to pieces, you sure do play the sibling act, huh?
砍死我哥哥之後 你們還上演兄弟情深的戲碼？
Let me tell you a funny story.
我給你講一個好笑的故事
You…
你…
Why did Moo-yeong leave without killing me?
無影為何不殺了我，反而走了？
It was his golden opportunity.
那可是個大好時機
What did he tell you?
他跟你說了什麼？
Gibberish.
胡言亂語
Let's go. Buy me naengmyeon.
走吧，請我吃冷麵
Hey, did you come running here because you were worried?
你是因為擔心我才跑過來的嗎？
Sheesh. Don't be ridiculous.
哎呀，別開玩笑了
Goodness, my brother sure is the best.
天哪，我弟弟最好了
Stop that. You're heavy.
別鬧了，你好重
Can't you walk straight?
不能好好走路嗎？
Geez. Look at the state of you.
真是的，看你這副樣子
About Jangsan Tiger…
萇山虎…
I called him on.
是我召喚來的
I had no idea he'd target you. I'm sorry, Hong-joo.
我不知道他會襲擊妳，對不起，紅酒
I wasn't asking for a confession.
我不是來興師問罪的
You get what you want?
你想要的東西拿到了嗎？
-What's your plan now? -I intend to revive my brother.
-接下來有什麼計劃？ -我想復活我哥哥
Your dead brother?
你死去的哥哥嗎？
No matter what you say, Lee Yeon and I will fight to the death.
無論妳怎麼說 我和李硯都會拼個你死我活
Then, give it up.
放棄吧
Act all you want, but you don't make a good villain.
不管你怎麼裝，都不像壞人
Can't you just stay by my side?
你不能乖乖待在我身邊嗎？
-As my precious friend? -Hong-joo.
-做我寶貴的朋友？ -紅酒
I don't care if he does it.
他勸我就算了
But don't you try to sway me.
請妳不要來勸我
If you try to sway me…
如果妳勸我的話…
-Damn it. My side is narrower! -What are you on about? My side's wider.
-該死，我這邊太窄了！ -胡說什麼？我這邊要寬一點
What the hell are you saying? Just shut up.
你什麼意思？閉嘴吧
Hey, Jae-yoo! You must be coming from some place far?
載宇，你從很遠的地方來的吧？
What are you doing in my room?
你們在我房間裡做什麼？
Now it's our room. The higher-ups gave permission.
現在是我們的房間了，上頭准許的
-Who do you mean? -Madame Ryu.
-你指的是誰？ -柳閣長
Geez. Lord Lee Yeon kicked me out, because of my snoring.
哎呀，因為我打鼾 被李硯大人趕出來了
-Hey, you even snore? -Did I not tell you not to cross the line?
-你竟然會打鼾？ -我不是叫你不要越線嗎？
Seriously! Look how petty this man is.
真是的！你看這個人多小氣
Jae-yoo. Mind your stuff. This prick's a thief.
載宇，看好你的東西，這混蛋是小偷
Hey, you bastard. I'm proud of my job!
混蛋，我以我的工作為榮！
-You'd be dead if not for Lord Lee Rang! -Both of you!
-要不是顧及李朗大人，我打死你！ -你們兩個！
I don't mind you guys fighting, but please don't speak to me.
打架沒關係，但請不要跟我講話
What? Well, he's a sassy punk.
什麼？真是個無禮的臭小子
What's your MBTI?
你的MBTI是什麼類型？
-What? -What's an em-bi-tae?
-什麼？ -“安比泰”是什麼？
MBTI.
MBTI
Is it Japanese?
是日語嗎？
-Man, I'm dying! -Oh, you mean Mandarin.
-去死！ -原來是中文
-Please save us! -Is no one there?
-救救我們！ -外面沒人嗎？
Honey, where on earth is this?
老公，這究竟是什麼地方？
-What crime did we even commit? -Someone's coming!
-我們到底犯了什麼罪？ -有人來了！
How many demons did we secure?
我們抓到了多少妖怪？
We have a decent number, but they are all weaklings.
數量不少，但是他們都很弱
We must complete the experiment to send them off to war.
我們必須完成試驗，將他們送上戰場
Increase the number of captures.
增加抓捕的人數
And secure the stronger ones.
設法抓到更強的妖怪
Joseon demons are more cunning than expected.
朝鮮妖怪比我們預想的還要狡猾
They know where to hide on their turf.
他們知道 如何在自己的地盤上躲藏起來
The Shinigami Mercenaries.
死神僱傭兵團
Summon them.
召喚他們吧
The Shinigami Mercenaries?
死神僱傭兵團？
They are the best in the field, but they're uncontrollable.
他們作戰能力最強，但是不受控制
I will do the controlling.
我會控制他們的
But, sir!
可是長官…
Experiment? What are they talking about?
試驗？他們在講什麼？
Honey, I don't like this. We have to get out of here!
老公，我不喜歡這樣 我們必須逃出去！
-Save us! -Please save us, please!
-救救我們！ -拜託救救我們吧！
I won't forgive you, Cheon Moo-yeong.
我不會原諒你的，千無影
Let me tell you a funny story.
我給你講一個好笑的故事
You…
你…
will die before you live a century.
活不到一百年
In the year 2020, you sacrifice yourself on your brother's behalf.
2020年 你會為你哥哥犧牲了自己
You will only die after being used your whole life.
你將在被利用殆盡後死去
Search the Gyeongseong grounds,
搜索京城境內
and find out who's behind this.
找出幕後主使
Your brother must be quite busy now.
你弟弟現在很忙吧
Why risk your life on a stupid bet?
為什麼為一個愚蠢的賭局拿命冒險？
I, too, wanted to live.
我也想活下去
If I win, revert his life span.
如果我贏了，恢復他的壽命
We must uproot the spirit of Joseon.
我們必須根除朝鮮精神
This isn't going to work.
這樣不行
We're on the same side, no?
我們同一陣線，不是嗎？
I'll help you.
我會幫你的
I wonder how many of them will make it out alive?
不知道有多少人能活著逃出來？
It will be a bloody night.
這將是一個血腥之夜
TRANSLATED BY TIFFANY HWANG
字幕翻譯：鄒琳